Generally, there are two ways to create Numpy arrays.
通常来讲 要创建 NumPy 数组有两种办法
First, using Numpy's array function to create
第一种 用 NumPy 的数组函数
them from other array-like objects such as regular Python lists.
借助 Python 常规列表等类数组对象进行创建
And second, using a variety of
第二种 使用各种 NumPy 内置函数
built-in Numpy functions that quickly generate specific types of arrays.
快速生成特定类型的数组
In this section, we will start with the first way.
本节先讲第一种办法
Let's import Numpy and create our first array.
导入 NumPy 创建第一个数组
Here's a one-dimensional array that contains integers.
这是个一维整数数组
Note that for clarity,
注意 为了授课方便
the examples throughout these lessons will use small, simple arrays.
课程会用简单的小数组作为例子
We'll start by creating one-dimensional or 1D Numpy arrays.
我们先创建一维 NumPy 数组 也就是 1D 数组
Let's print the array we just created,
把刚才创建的数组
as well as, it's type.
及其类型输出出来
You can see that the type is Numpy's ndarray or n-dimensional array.
可以看到类型是 numpy.ndarray 也就是 n 维数组
Numpy arrays have useful attributes that provide
NumPy 的数组有些很实用的属性
us information about them in a very intuitive way.
为我们提供了一些很直观的信息
For example, this dtype attribute.
比如这个属性 dtype
Dtype returns the data type of the elements in that array.
dtype 会返回数组元素的数据类型
Notice, dtype is different from the datatype of the array itself.
注意 dtype 和数组本身的数据类型不同
This d type let's us know that the elements of X
dtype 告诉我们的是
are stored in memory a signed 64-bit integers.
元素 x 在 ndarray 中存放的是有符号的 64 位整数
An additional advantage of Numpy is that it handles more datatypes than Python.
可以处理的数据类型比 Python 多 是NumPy 的另一个优势
You can check out all the different datatypes supported by Numpy in it's documentation.
想了解 NumPy 支持的所有数据类型 请查看相关文献
Another useful attribute is shape.
形状 shape 是 NumPy 的另一实用属性
This returns a tuple of n positive integers that specifies
该属性会返回一个由 n 个正整数组成的元组
the sizes of each dimension n being the number of dimensions in the array.
说明数组每个维度的大小 其中 n 为数组的维数
X has one dimension.
x 只有一个维度
So, shape returns an integer indicating the length of the array, five.
所以 shape 返回了一个整数 指明数组的长度为 5
If we had a two-dimensional array,
如果数组是二维的
this shape attribute would return a tuple with two values,
那属性 shape 会返回一个由两个值组成的元组
one for the number of rows and one for the number of columns.
一个值指行数 另一个指列数
To see this, let's create a two-dimensional array from a nested Python list.
我们来用嵌套的 Python 列表 创建一个二维数组 看看具体是怎么样的
Here is one that contains integers.
这个数组由整数组成
And let's print an additional attribute size.
我们还要输出一个属性 size
Looking at the tuple returned by shape,
观察 shape 返回的元组
we know that Y has two dimensions since there are two elements.
由于其中有两个元素 所以 Y 有两个维度
One is for the size of the first dimension which is the number of rows,
一个是第一维度的大小 也就是行数 为 4
four, and the other is for the second dimension,
另一个是第二维度的大小
which is the number of columns, three.
也就是列数 为 3
The size attribute gives us the total number of elements in Y which is 12.
属性 size 则告诉我们 Y 总共有 12 个元素
Let's pause for a second to introduce some useful terminology.
我们先来讲些重要的术语
In general, we say that an array with n dimensions has a rank n. So,
通常 我们说 n 维数组有 n 秩
we refer to the 1D array we created earlier as
所以我们称刚才创建的一维数组有 1 个秩
a rank one-array and we refer to the 2D array we just created as a rank two-array.
称刚才创建的二维数组有 2 个秩
For our next example,
接下来
let's create a rank one-array that contains strings,
我们要创建一个秩为 1 的字符串数组
and let's print those same attributes.
输出上述属性
The type of the array object itself isn't any different,
数组对象本身的类型没有变化
it's still just a Numpy array.
仍然是 NumPy 数组
However, the dtype of this array is different.
但数组的 dtype 则不同了
Here elements are stored as unicode strings of five characters.
这里元素以 unicode 字符串的形式存储着 该字符串由五个字符组成
Notice that when Numpy creates an array,
注意 创建数组时
it automatically assigns it's dtype
NumPy 会自动
based on the type of the elements you used to create the array.
根据数组创建元素的类型来给 dtype 赋值
But what happens when we try to create a Numpy array
但如果我们用列表创建一个
with a list that contains both integers and strings?
同时包含整数和字符串的 NumPy 数组呢？
We can see that even though the Python list had mixed datatypes,
我们会发现 虽然 Python 列表有多种数据类型
the array function created a Numpy array with elements of all the same datatype namely,
函数 array 创建出来的 NumPy 数组会让元素保持相同的数据类型
unicode strings of 21 characters.
也即由 21 个字符组成的 unicode 字符串
Remember, unlike Python lists,
记住 与 Python 列表不同
Numpy arrays must contain elements of the same type.
NumPy 数组元素的数据类型必须一致
Up until now, we've only used elements that were integers or strings.
到目前为止 我们只用了整数和字符串元素
Let's try another example with mixed datatypes using integers and floats.
我们再来看一个混合数据类型的例子 这次用整数和浮点数
When we input a list with both integers and floats,
当我们输入一个既有整数也有浮点数的列表时
Numpy assigns all elements,
NumPy 将所有元素的 dtype
the float 64 dtype,
设为 64 位浮点型
this is called upcasting.
这就叫向上转型
Since all the elements of a Numpy array must be of the same type,
由于 NumPy 数组中的所有元素必须具备相同类型
Numpy upcasts the integers in the array to
所以 NumPy 会将数组里的整数向上转型为浮点数
floats in order to avoid losing precision in numerical computations.
以免影响数值计算的准确性
Numpy also allows you to specify
你还可以用 NumPy 指定
a particular dtype you want to assign to the elements of an array,
数组元素的 dtype
you can do this using the keyword dtype in the array function.
只需在函数 array 里用关键字 dtype 即可
Here, you can see Numpy created an array of
你可以看到 这里 NumPy 生成了一个整数数组
ints even though we passed it a list of floats.
而我们输入的列表数据是浮点型的
Specifying the datatype of the elements in
指定 NumPy 数组元素的数据类型
a Numpy array can be useful in cases where you don't want to accidentally
能避免不小心
choose the wrong datatype or when you only need
选到错误的数据类型
a certain amount of precision in your calculations and want to save memory.
如果比起计算准确性 你更想节省内存 那你也可以指定数据类型
Once you create a Numpy array,
创建好 NumPy 数组
you may want to save it to a file to be read later or to be used by another program.
你可能想将其保存到文档中 以便稍后读取或导入其它程序里
Numpy provides a way to save the arrays into files for later use.
要将数组保存到文档中以备后用 可用 NumPy 提供的一种方法
We can save X into the current directory like this.
我们可以像这样把 x 存储到当前目录下
This saves the array into a file named my array dot npy.
这样就可以把数组存储到文档 my_array.npy 中了
You can later load this file into a variable by using the load function like this.
稍后你可以用函数 load 将文档加载到变量里 就像这样